<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Praveen Akkiraji on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/praveen-akkiraji/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Praveen Akkiraji on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>hari@dasarpai.com (Dr. Hari Thapliyaal)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hari@dasarpai.com (Dr. Hari Thapliyaal)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2025 Dr. Hari Thapliyaal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/praveen-akkiraji/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Agentic AI? Interview with Praveen Akkiraju at CXOTalk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/booksummary/Interview-What-is-Agentic-AI-Interview-Praveen-Akkiraji-at-CXOTalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hari@dasarpai.com (Dr. Hari Thapliyaal)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/booksummary/Interview-What-is-Agentic-AI-Interview-Praveen-Akkiraji-at-CXOTalk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;../../assets/images/booksummary/7538-Interview-What-is-Agentic-AI-Interview-Praveen-Akkiraji-at-CXOTalk.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;What is Agentic AI? Interview with Praveen Akkiraju at CXOTalk&#34; /&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h1 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Praveen Akkiraju w/ Michael Krigsman @ CXOTalk - 853 
    &lt;div id=&#34;praveen-akkiraju-w-michael-krigsman--cxotalk---853&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#praveen-akkiraju-w-michael-krigsman--cxotalk---853&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in learning more about agentic AI, or you have any of these questions then without answer of fuzzy answer then this interview is for you.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Interview Questions 
    &lt;div id=&#34;interview-questions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#interview-questions&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is agentic AI? Please give us a background of AI as it relates to this and why agentic AI has suddenly erupted in popularity recently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When we talk about agentic AI, agents, intelligent tasks, and intelligent workflows, what are we discussing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How is this different from horrible chatbots that enterprise software companies sell as &amp;ldquo;great customer experience&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When we talk about autonomous, can you elaborate on that? To some degree, that term separates agentic AI from traditional chatbots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the reasoning step the crucial aspect that distinguishes agents from other types of computer science problems or applications?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can we call these AI agents instead of trying to make up a new word?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What percentage of agentic work is focused on enterprise back-office processes? Is it more fruitful than front-end human interaction tasks?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the current generation, are the agentic AI layers all based on neural networks or LLM models, or are some of them more traditional symbolic AI kinds of code?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Won&amp;rsquo;t these agents replace white-collar jobs also? Are these agents the death of consultants?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the potential harms that may come from automating decision-making using agentic AI at scale?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can you describe how we create agents and maybe some of the companies out there who are working on this?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can you talk about the right type of data that needs to be collected to implement these agents?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Should the agents be transparent on how they came to their conclusions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can you help technology leaders see through the agentic hype? When evaluating these technologies, what should they look for?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do you ensure that agentic AI doesn&amp;rsquo;t go off the rails over time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do enterprise business architects have a role in AI, and should they report directly to the CEO?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are these agents solely focused on optimizing tasks, or do they incorporate guardrails in their design?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the ultimate goal of these agents? Is it to replace people? Should employees train these agents so they won&amp;rsquo;t have a job anymore?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What types of jobs are most likely to be replaced by agentic AI, and which jobs will be augmented instead?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do models like GPT-o1 and Google&amp;rsquo;s self-correcting reinforcement learning improve reasoning and planning for agentic AI?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do concepts like chain-of-thought reasoning and reflection loops contribute to improving agentic AI?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What specific applications or use cases highlight the strengths of agentic AI in enterprise settings?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the challenges associated with trust and safety in deploying agentic AI at scale?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do AI agents differ from traditional applications or systems of record in terms of architecture and functionality?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What role does the data layer play in enabling the functionality and accuracy of agentic AI?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does RAG (Retrieval Augmented Generation) help enhance model performance without retraining?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the benefits and trade-offs of using open-source frameworks like LangChain or BabyAGI for building agentic AI?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do enterprises balance non-deterministic outputs from LLMs with the need for deterministic outcomes in applications?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yTEB3j8tmM8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Full Interview - What is Agentic AI? Autonomous Agents and Intelligent Workflows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
