<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Certifications on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/certifications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Certifications on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>hari@dasarpai.com (Dr. Hari Thapliyaal)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hari@dasarpai.com (Dr. Hari Thapliyaal)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2025 Dr. Hari Thapliyaal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 12:10:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/certifications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Why 6sigmastudy Certification?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pmblog/Why-6sigmastudy-Certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 12:10:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hari@dasarpai.com (Dr. Hari Thapliyaal)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pmblog/Why-6sigmastudy-Certification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;../../assets/images/pmblog/1038-pmlogy-post.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Why 6sigmastudy Certification? 
    &lt;div id=&#34;why-6sigmastudy-certification&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#why-6sigmastudy-certification&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;6sigmastudy&lt;sup&gt;™&lt;/sup&gt; Six Sigma Certifications&lt;/th&gt;
          &lt;th&gt;Other Six Sigma Certifications&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Biggest accreditation body for Six Sigma certifications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;6sigmastudy&lt;sup&gt;™&lt;/sup&gt; is the biggest accreditation body for Six Sigma certifications. 6sigmastudy&lt;sup&gt;™&lt;/sup&gt; has the largest Authorized Training Partner (A.T.P.) network of 2,100+ partners in 90+ countries.&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Other Six Sigma accreditation bodies are smaller and not as well-recognized as 6sigmastudy&lt;sup&gt;™&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Students from 25,000+ companies in 150+ countries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;6sigmastudy&lt;sup&gt;™&lt;/sup&gt; has trained/certified more than 750,000 persons in delivering successful projects.&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Other Six Sigma accreditation bodies are not as popular or as widely accepted.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Industry-wide acceptance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;The knowledge gained by getting a 6sigmastudy™ certification is universal in its application and has been applied by organizations in diverse projects spanning an eclectic mix of industries.&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Other Six Sigma certifications are not accepted in all industries. Most of the time the learning from these certifications applies only to specific industries.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Established name in Six Sigma certifications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;6sigmastudy™’s certification training is provided through its Authorized Training Partners (A.T.P.s) all across the globe.   With more than 2,100+ A.T.P.s globally, 6sigmastudy™ has the widest network of accredited training companies offering its certifications. 6sigmastudy™ certifications are widely reputed and accepted by various Fortune 500 companies such as Apple, IBM, HP, Bank of America, AT&amp;amp;T, Dell, Verizon, Lockheed Martin, and PepsiCo.&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Other Six Sigma certification companies conduct their training through a much smaller network of trainers or training companies, and do not have the same level of credibility in the market that 6sigmastudy™ has.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Active Discussions to share and learn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;6sigmastudy&lt;sup&gt;™&lt;/sup&gt; engages the Six Sigma/Lean and Quality Management community through active discussions on LinkedIn, Twitter, Facebook, multiple&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Usually, other certification providers do not have such high activity discussion forums to engage their community.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Multiple free resources for Six Sigma Community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;6sigmastudy™ provides a wide range of free resources such as 5+ hours of high-quality videos, useful case studies, interactive mobile apps, blogs, and articles, thereby contributing to the increased awareness of Six Sigma in the Six Sigma communities.&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;No other Six Sigma Certification provides high quality content and free resources to students in multiple formats. The main focus of such certification providers is to get students to their paid classes, rather than help students succeed with best practices.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Free “Six Sigma Yellow Belt” – SSYB™ Course&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Through its free Six Sigma Yellow Belt (SSYB™) Course, 6sigmastudy™ not only introduces Six Sigma concepts to professionals but also helps them get an introductory certification for free. This free certification includes approximately 10 hours of free online self-study through videos, case studies, and guides. The free SSYB™ certification is a great way to introduce Six Sigma to all employees in your organization. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dasarpai.com/forms/course-interest/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Enroll in Free SSYB™ Training&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Other Six Sigma certifications usually do not provide any free resources or help for students to get a basic idea of Six Sigma concepts. In most cases, professionals are required to pay upfront before even getting their first lesson on Six Sigma.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Credible and standard testing environment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;With an emphasis on providing candidates with a reliable and credible testing environment, we conduct our certification exams using our live online proctoring system unlike other certifying bodies. This allows you to take your certification exams from the comfort of your home. All exams will be proctored live and videos of the exams will be recorded and reviewed by our assessment team.&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Other Six Sigma certifications do not have a standardized examination. Most of them only require candidates to be present for a workshop and take a test, the result of which has no bearing on whether the candidate qualifies for the certification. These kinds of certifications never have the credibility companies require to select candidates for key roles.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9. Teaching methodology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;6sigmastudy™ A.T.P.s use a scientifically proven and highly interactive teaching methodology including role-plays, case studies, and simulations explaining the key Six Sigma concepts for their Six Sigma certification courses. To ensure an enriching learning experience for all our students, each trainer associated with a 6sigmastudy™ A.T.P. is required to be an accredited 6sigmastudy Certified Trainer (SSCT®).&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Other Six Sigma certification “workshops” are actually lectures. They are not engaging or interactive and most of the times involve delegates (sometimes more than 50 in a class) hearing an instructor for hours without any structured role plays or case studies.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Experienced 6sigmastudy™ trainers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Any person who is qualified as a 6sigmastudy Certified Trainer (SSCT®) undergoes a rigorous assessment process and he or she has to exhibit proficiency in the concepts of Six Sigma. All trainers are required to successfully pass two 6sigmastudy&lt;sup&gt;™&lt;/sup&gt; certification exams before they are eligible to teach. Moreover, all feedback from students about their respective trainers is reviewed and all 6sigmastudy™ trainers regularly participate in “Train-the-Trainer” sessions, which help them understand the nuances of our certifications and further cement their understanding of the Six Sigma methodology.&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Usually, other Six Sigma Certifications do not have such strict requirements for trainer accreditation, and thus the quality of their instructors may not be very high.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Six Sigma?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pmblog/What-is-Six-Sigma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 04:16:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hari@dasarpai.com (Dr. Hari Thapliyaal)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pmblog/What-is-Six-Sigma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;../../assets/images/pmblog/1038-pmlogy-post.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;What is Six Sigma?&#34; /&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h1 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;What is Six Sigma? 
    &lt;div id=&#34;what-is-six-sigma&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#what-is-six-sigma&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Six Sigma Introduction 
    &lt;div id=&#34;six-sigma-introduction&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#six-sigma-introduction&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six Sigma is a data-driven, customer-focused, and result-oriented methodology that uses statistical tools and techniques to systematically eliminate defects and inefficiencies to improve processes. It is a systematic method to measure and analyze the business processes to identify critical factors affecting business results, thereby improving the processes and establishing controls around the improved processes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PMI-ACP Exam Preparation Books</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pmblog/PMI-ACP-Exam-Preparation-Books/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 05:53:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hari@dasarpai.com (Dr. Hari Thapliyaal)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pmblog/PMI-ACP-Exam-Preparation-Books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;../../assets/images/pmblog/1030-PMI-ACP-Exam-Prep-min.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;PMI-ACP Exam Preparation Books 
    &lt;div id=&#34;pmi-acp-exam-preparation-books&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#pmi-acp-exam-preparation-books&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like PMBOK PMI does not have any guide book or standard for the PMI-ACP exam. PMI has published an exam content outline on their website and as per that you are recommended to study the following 11 books thoroughly before you go for the PMI-ACP exam.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;List of Recommended Books 
    &lt;div id=&#34;list-of-recommended-books&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#list-of-recommended-books&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agile Retrospectives: Making Good Teams Great, &lt;strong&gt;Author&lt;/strong&gt;: Esther Derby, Diana Larsen, Ken Schwaber, ISBN #0977616649&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agile Software Development: The Cooperative Game – 2nd Edition, &lt;strong&gt;Author&lt;/strong&gt;: Alistair Cockburn, ISBN #0321482751&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Software Project Manager’s Bridge to Agility, &lt;strong&gt;Author&lt;/strong&gt;: Michele Sliger, Stacia Broderick, ISBN #0321502752&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coaching Agile Teams, &lt;strong&gt;Author&lt;/strong&gt;: Lyssa Adkins, ISBN #0321637704&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agile Project Management: Creating Innovative Products – 2nd Edition, &lt;strong&gt;Author&lt;/strong&gt;: Jim Highsmith, ISBN #0321658396&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Becoming Agile in an imperfect world, &lt;strong&gt;Author&lt;/strong&gt;: Greg Smith, Ahmed Sidky, ISBN #1933988258&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agile Estimating and Planning, &lt;strong&gt;Author&lt;/strong&gt;: MikeCohn, ISBN #0131479415&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Art of Agile Development, &lt;strong&gt;Author&lt;/strong&gt;: James Shore, ISBN #0596527675&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User Stories Applied: For Agile Software Development, &lt;strong&gt;Author&lt;/strong&gt;: MikeCohn, ISBN #0321205685&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agile Project Managementwith Scrum, &lt;strong&gt;Author&lt;/strong&gt;: Ken Schwaber, ISBN #073561993X&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lean-Agile Software Development: Achieving EnterpriseAgility, &lt;strong&gt;Author&lt;/strong&gt;: Alan Shalloway, Guy Beaver, James R.Trott, ISBN #0321532899&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Other Good Agile books 
    &lt;div id=&#34;other-good-agile-books&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#other-good-agile-books&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agile modeling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managing Agile projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agile Product Management with Scrum: Creating products that customer love- &lt;strong&gt;Author&lt;/strong&gt;: Roman Pichler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lean Agile sofware development: Achieving Enterprise Agility, &lt;strong&gt;Author&lt;/strong&gt;: Alan Shaloway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lean agile software Development, &lt;strong&gt;Author&lt;/strong&gt;: Alan Shalloway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
