<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beginners on </title>
    <link>/tags/beginners/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Beginners on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>hari@dasarpai.com (Dr. Hari Thapliyaal)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hari@dasarpai.com (Dr. Hari Thapliyaal)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2025 Dr. Hari Thapliyaal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/beginners/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Vedanta For Beginners</title>
      <link>/wiaposts/vedanta-for-beginners/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hari@dasarpai.com (Dr. Hari Thapliyaal)</author>
      <guid>/wiaposts/vedanta-for-beginners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;/assets/images/wiapost/5149-Vedanta-For-Beginners.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Vedanta For Beginners&#34; /&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h1 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Vedanta For Beginners 
    &lt;div id=&#34;vedanta-for-beginners&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#vedanta-for-beginners&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h1&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;By Sri Swami Sivananda, Founder of The Divine 
    &lt;div id=&#34;by-sri-swami-sivananda-founder-of-the-divine&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#by-sri-swami-sivananda-founder-of-the-divine&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BASICS OF VEDANTA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The fourfold &lt;strong&gt;Antahkarana&lt;/strong&gt; or the internal organ: Manas (mind), Buddhi (intellect), Chitta (memory or subconscious), Ahamkara (egoism).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are three bodies or &lt;strong&gt;Shariras&lt;/strong&gt;: Sthoola-Sharira (gross physical body), Sukshma or Linga-Sharira (subtle body), Karana-Sharira (causal body).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are &lt;strong&gt;five Koshas&lt;/strong&gt; or sheaths &lt;strong&gt;covering the Jiva&lt;/strong&gt;: Annamaya (food sheath), Pranamaya (vital sheath), Manomaya (mental sheath), Vijnanamaya (intellectual sheath), Anandamaya (bliss-sheath).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are &lt;strong&gt;six Bhava-Vikaras&lt;/strong&gt; or modifications &lt;strong&gt;of the body&lt;/strong&gt;: Asti (existence), Jayate  &lt;br&gt;
(birth), Vardhate (growth), Viparinamate (change), Apakshiyate (decay), Vinashyati (death).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are &lt;strong&gt;five gross elements&lt;/strong&gt;: Akasha (sky), Vayu (air), Agni (fire), Apah (water),  &lt;br&gt;
Prithivi (earth).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are &lt;strong&gt;five Upa-pranas&lt;/strong&gt; or subsidiary vital airs: Naga, Kurma, Krikara, Devadatta,  &lt;br&gt;
Dhananjaya.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are &lt;strong&gt;six Urmis&lt;/strong&gt; or waves (of the ocean of Samsara): Shoka (grief), Moha (confusion or delusion), Kshut (hunger), Pipasa (thirst), Jara (decay or old age), Mrityu (death).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are &lt;strong&gt;six Vairis&lt;/strong&gt; or enemies: Kama (passion), Krodha (anger), Lobha (greed), Moha  &lt;br&gt;
(infatuation or delusion or confusion), Mada (pride), Matsarya (jealousy).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maya&lt;/strong&gt; is twofold: Vidya (knowledge), Avidya (ignorance).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vidya&lt;/strong&gt; or knowledge is twofold: Para (higher), Apara (lower).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avasthas&lt;/strong&gt; or states &lt;strong&gt;of consciousness&lt;/strong&gt; are three: Jagrat (waking), Svapna (dreaming),  &lt;br&gt;
Sushupti (deep sleep).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saktis&lt;/strong&gt; are two: Avarana (veil), Vikshepa (distraction).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jnana-Bhumikas&lt;/strong&gt; or degrees of knowledge are seven: Subheccha, Vicharana,  &lt;br&gt;
Tanumanasi, Sattvapatti, Asamsakti, Padarthabhavana, Turiya.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ajnana-Bhumikas&lt;/strong&gt; or degrees of ignorance are seven: Bija-Jagrat, Jagrat, Maha-Jagrat,  &lt;br&gt;
Jagrat-Svapna, Svapna, Svapna-Jagrat, Sushupti.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;nature of Atman&lt;/strong&gt; or Brahman is threefold: Sat (existence), Chit (consciousness),  &lt;br&gt;
Ananda (bliss).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Granthis or knots of the heart&lt;/strong&gt; are three: Avidya (ignorance), Kama (desire), Karma (action).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;defects of the Jiva&lt;/strong&gt; are three: Mala (impurity), Vikshepa (distraction), Avarana (veil  &lt;br&gt;
of ignorance).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Vrittis or modes of the mind&lt;/strong&gt; are two: Vishayakara-Vritti (objective psychosis),  &lt;br&gt;
Brahmakara-Vritti (Infinite Psychosis).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gunas&lt;/strong&gt; or qualities &lt;strong&gt;of Prakriti&lt;/strong&gt; are three: Sattva (light and purity), Rajas (activity and  &lt;br&gt;
passion), Tamas (darkness and inertia).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Puris consisting the subtle body&lt;/strong&gt; are eight: Jnana-Indriyas, Karma-Indriyas,  &lt;br&gt;
Pranas, Antahkarana, Tanmatras, Avidya, Kama, Karma.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Karmas&lt;/strong&gt; are three: Sanchita, Prarabdha, Agami.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;nature of a thing&lt;/strong&gt; is fivefold: Asti, Bhati, Priya, Nama, Rupa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bhedas&lt;/strong&gt; or differences are three: Svagata, Sajatiya, Vijatiya.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lakshanas&lt;/strong&gt; or definitions &lt;strong&gt;of the nature of Brahma&lt;/strong&gt;n are two: Svarupalakshana,  &lt;br&gt;
Tatasthalakshana.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dhatus&lt;/strong&gt; or constituents &lt;strong&gt;of the body&lt;/strong&gt; are seven: Rasa, (chyle), Asra (blood), Mamsa  &lt;br&gt;
(flesh), Medas (fat), Asthi (bone), Majja (marrow), Shukla (semen).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are &lt;strong&gt;four states of the Jnani&lt;/strong&gt;: Brahmavit, Brahmavidvara, Brahmavidvariyan,  &lt;br&gt;
Brahmavidvarishtha.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anubandhas&lt;/strong&gt; or matters of discussion (themes) in Vedanta are four: Adhikari (fit  &lt;br&gt;
aspirant), Vishaya (subject), Sambandha (connection), Prayojyna (fruit or result).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bhavanas or imaginations of the mind&lt;/strong&gt; are three: Samshayabhavana (doubt), Asambhavana (feeling of impossibility), Viparitabhavana (perverted or wrong thinking).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Malas&lt;/strong&gt; or impurities &lt;strong&gt;of the mind&lt;/strong&gt; are thirteen: Raga, Dvesha, Kama, Krodha, Lobha,  &lt;br&gt;
Moha, Mada, Matsarya, Irshya, Asuya, Dambha, Darpa, Ahamkara.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kleshas or worldly afflictions&lt;/strong&gt; are five: Avidya, (ignorance), Asmita (egoism), Raga  &lt;br&gt;
(love), Dvesha (hatred), Abhinivesha (clinging to body and earthly life).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taapas&lt;/strong&gt; or sufferings are three: Adhidaivika, Adhibhautika, Adhyatmika.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pramanas&lt;/strong&gt; or proofs &lt;strong&gt;of knowledg&lt;/strong&gt;e are six: Pratyaksha (perception), Anumana  &lt;br&gt;
(inference), Upamana (comparison), Agama (scripture), Arthapatti (presumption), Anupalabdhi (non-apprehension).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minds&lt;/strong&gt; are two: Ashuddha (impure), Shuddha (pure).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meditations&lt;/strong&gt; are two: Saguna, Nirguna.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Muktas&lt;/strong&gt; are two: Jivanmukta, Videhamukta.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Muktis&lt;/strong&gt; are two: Krama-Mukti, Sadyo-Mukti.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samadhis&lt;/strong&gt; are two: Savikalpa, Nirvikalpa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jnana&lt;/strong&gt; is twofold: Paroksha (indirect), Aparoksha (direct).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prakriti&lt;/strong&gt; is twofold: Para, Apara.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apara Prakriti is eightfold:&lt;/strong&gt; Earth, Water, Fire, Air, Ether, Mind, Intellect, Egoism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prasthanas&lt;/strong&gt; or the regulated texts of Vedanta are three: Upanishads (Shruti),  &lt;br&gt;
Brahmasutras (Nyaya), Bhagavad-Gita (Smriti).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are &lt;strong&gt;two varieties of Granthas&lt;/strong&gt; or Texts: Pramana-Granthas, Prameya-Granthas.  &lt;br&gt;
The texts are again divided into two sections: Prakriya-Granthas and Shastra-Granthas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eshanas or desires&lt;/strong&gt; are three: Daraishana (desire for wife), Vittishana (desire for wealth), Lokaishana (desire for this world and the other world).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Species of beings are four&lt;/strong&gt;: Jarayuja (born of womb), Andaja (born of egg), Svedaja  &lt;br&gt;
(born of sweat), Udbhijja (born of earth).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The sentinels to the door of salvation are four&lt;/strong&gt;: Santi (peace), Santosha (contentment), Vichara (enquiry or ratiocination), Satsanga (company of the wise).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;States of the mind&lt;/strong&gt; are five: Kshipta (distracted), Mudha (dull), Vikshipta (slightly  &lt;br&gt;
distracted), Ekagra (concentrated), Niruddha (inhibited).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gates of the body&lt;/strong&gt; are nine: Two ears, two eyes, mouth, nose, navel, genital, anus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avarana-Sakti&lt;/strong&gt; is twofold: Asattva-Avarana, Abhana-Avarana.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vikshepa-Sakti&lt;/strong&gt; is threefold: Kriyasakti, Icchasakti, Jnanasakti.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satta or existence&lt;/strong&gt; is of three varieties: Paramarthika (absolutely real), Vyavaharika  &lt;br&gt;
(phenomenal), Pratibhasika (apparent or illusory).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knowledge&lt;/strong&gt; is of two varieties: Svarupajnana (knowledge of the essential nature),  &lt;br&gt;
Vrittijnana (psychological or intellectual knowledge).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obstacles to Samadhi&lt;/strong&gt; are four: Laya (torpidity), Vikshepa (distraction), Kashaya  &lt;br&gt;
(attachment), Rasasvada (enjoyment of objective happiness).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;nature of the cosmic&lt;/strong&gt; person (Isvara) is threefold: Virat, Hiranyagarbha, Isvara.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;nature of the individual&lt;/strong&gt; person (Jiva) is threefold: Vishva, Taijasa, Prajna.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cognition is effected&lt;/strong&gt; through two factors: Vritti-Vyapti (pervasion of the psychosis),  &lt;br&gt;
Phala-Vyapti (pervasion of the result or consciousness).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The meaning of the &lt;strong&gt;Tat-Tvam-Asi&lt;/strong&gt; Mahavakyas is twofold: Vachyartha (literal  &lt;br&gt;
meaning), Lakshyartha (indicative meaning).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vedantic enquiry is practised through the methods of&lt;/strong&gt;: Anvaya-Vyatireka, Atadvyavritti, Neti-neti doctrine, Adhyaropa-Apavada, Nyayas (illustrations), etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The meaning of the great dictum&lt;/strong&gt; Tat-Tvam-Asi is ascertained through the considerations of Jahadajahallakshana or Bhagatyaga-lakshana, Samanadhikarana, Visheshanavisheshyabhava, Lakshya-lakshanasambandha.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The important Vedas in Vedanta&lt;/strong&gt; are: Vivartavada, Ajativada, Drishti-Srishtivada, Srishti-Drishtivada, Avacchedavada, Pratibimbavada, Ekajivavada, Anekajivavada, bhasavada.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vedantic Contemplation is threefold: Sravana, Manana, Nididhyasana.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Twenty-four Tattvas or Principles of the manifestation of Mula Prakriti:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
