<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Browser Tools on </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/browser-tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Browser Tools on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>hari@dasarpai.com (Dr. Hari Thapliyaal)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hari@dasarpai.com (Dr. Hari Thapliyaal)</webMaster>
    <copyright>© 2025 Dr. Hari Thapliyaal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/browser-tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>My Favorite Chrome Extensions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/myfab-chrome-extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hari@dasarpai.com (Dr. Hari Thapliyaal)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/dsblog/myfab-chrome-extensions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;../../assets/images/dsresources/dsr111-My-Favorite-Chrome-Extensions.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;My Favorite Chrome Extensions&#34; /&gt;
      
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h1 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;My Favorite Chrome Extensions 
    &lt;div id=&#34;my-favorite-chrome-extensions&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#my-favorite-chrome-extensions&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Application Launcher For Drive (by Google) : Open Drive files directly from your browser in compatible applications installed on your computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bardeen - automate manual work : Automate manual work with one click! Connect 30+ apps, scrape the web, and boost your productivity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bell of Mindfulness : A bell that reminds us to breathe and be mindful of our body and mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ChatGPT for Google : Show ChatGPT response alongside search engine results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cisco Webex Extension : Join Webex meetings using Google Chrome ™&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ColorZilla : Advanced Eyedropper, Color Picker, Gradient Generator and other colorful goodies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dark Mode - Dark Reader for Сhrome : Dark Mode a classic dark theme for every website. Switch website to dark reader and for night and daily browsing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DeepSeek AI : Chat with DeepSeek AI – Boost your creativity and productivity using DeepSeek R1, the ultimate AI-powered browser tool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editor for Docs, Sheets &amp;amp; Slides : View, edit and select the layout of Google Docs, Sheets, and Slides with an easy access via extension menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eightify: Youtube Summary with ChatGPT : Youtube video summaries with ChatGPT. Extract key ideas from Youtube videos with GPT.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Glasp Web Highlighter: PDF &amp;amp; Web Highlight : AI-powered Web Highlighter for Websites, PDF, and YouTube videos. YouTube Summary with ChatGPT, Claude, and Gemini.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Glasp: Social Web Highlight &amp;amp; YouTube Summary : Take notes and add highlights on web pages. Discover and save articles from friends. A tool for writers, avid readers, and thinkers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GoFullPage - Full Page Screen Capture : Capture a screenshot of your current page in entirety and reliably—without requesting any extra permissions!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Dictionary (by Google) : View definitions easily as you browse the web.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Docs Offline : Edit, create, and view your documents, spreadsheets, and presentations — all without internet access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Input Tools : Input Tools lets you type in the language of your choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Keep Chrome Extension : Save to Google Keep in a single click!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Scholar Button : Lookup scholarly articles as you browse the web.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google Translate : View translations easily as you browse the web. By the Google Translate team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grammar &amp;amp; Spell Checker — LanguageTool : Check your texts for spelling and grammar problems everywhere on the web&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grammar Checker &amp;amp; Paraphraser – LanguageTool : Instantly Enhance Your Texts with LanguageTool’s Grammar Checker and Paraphrasing Tool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grammarly: AI Writing and Grammar Checker App : Improve your writing with all-in-one assistance—including generative AI, grammar check, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Headline Studio by CoSchedule : The headline analyzer from CoSchedule enables you to create headlines that drives maximum traffic, clicks, &amp;amp; SEO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highlighter : Highlight text on websites with a simple right-click or keyboard shortcut. Saves highlights on your device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IPEVO Whiteboard : IPEVO Whiteboard for Chromebook is specifically designed to create an interactive whiteboard with IPEVO IW2 on your Chromebook.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keepa - Amazon Price Tracker : Adds price history charts and the option to be alerted on price drops to all supported Amazon sites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keyword Tool Dominator : Keyword Tool Dominator Extension&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keywords Everywhere - Keyword Tool : Keyword search volume, cpc and competition for 15+ websites like Google™ Search Console, YouTube™, Amazon™ &amp;amp; more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marinara: Pomodoro® Assistant : Pomodoro® time management assistant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markdown Viewer : Dark Mode • Themes • Autoreload • Mermaid Diagrams • MathJax • ToC • Syntax Highlighting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mendeley Web Importer : Fast, convenient import of references and PDFs to your Mendeley Reference Manager library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microsoft Bing Search for Chrome : Set Microsoft Bing as your default search provider&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MindStudio : MindStudio Chrome Extension&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MozBar : MozBar from Moz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neeva AI Search : AI powered, instant answers with citations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Office Editing for Docs, Sheets &amp;amp; Slides : View and edit Microsoft Word, Excel, and PowerPoint files with Google Docs, Sheets, and Slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OneTab : Save up to 95% memory and reduce tab clutter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open in Colab : Open a Github-hosted notebook in Google Colab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ParagraphAI - Write Better, Faster : ParagraphAI is an AI-powered writing tool that crafts perfectly curated content for all your writing needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pomodoro® Assistant : Pomodoro® time management assistan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Power Thesaurus : Use the power of synonyms by button in toolbar, right-click or by word selection on any page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pronounce: Speech and Pronunciation Checker : Speak confidently with instant feedback on any conversation from an AI speech coach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read Aloud: A Text to Speech Voice Reader : Read aloud the current web-page article with one click, using text to speech (TTS). Supports 40+ languages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RoboForm Password Manager : RoboForm Password Manager makes your life easier by remembering passwords and logging you into websites automatically&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sci-Hub : Science Paper Research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selenium IDE : Selenium Record and Playback tool for ease of getting acquainted with Selenium WebDriver.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sider: Chat with all AI models (DeepSeek, Gemini, Claude, etc.) : AI sidebar support chat with all AI models (DeepSeek, Gemini, Claude, etc.) for advanced AI search, read, and write.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Signer.Digital Digital Signature, PKI : Digital Signature of eReturns, PDF &amp;amp; Web User Auth, RSA Encryption/Decryption, Certificate Enrollment/Download on Smartcard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simplescraper — a fast and free web scraper : A web scraper that&amp;rsquo;s fast, free and simple to use. Scrape website data and table data in seconds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slido : Engage your audience with live polling and Q&amp;amp;A without ever leaving Google Slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star History : A chrome extension showing star history graph of current GitHub repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tabbed Postman - REST Client :&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Table Capture : Copies HTML tables to the clipboard or exports them to Microsoft Excel, CSV, Google Sheets, Office 365, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tag Assistant Legacy (by Google) : Tag Assistant helps to troubleshoot installation of various Google tags including Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk-to-ChatGPT : Talk to ChatGPT through your microphone and hear its responses with a voice. Uses speech recognition and text-to-speech technologies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transliterate South Asian Scripts : Transliterate South Asian Scripts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ubersuggest - SEO and Keyword Discovery : Keyword search volume, CPC and insights for all keywords you search. Works with Google, YouTube and Amazon. SEO tool by Neil Patel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Web Scraper - GetData.IO : Turn any webpage into an API in 3 click&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WhatFont : The easiest way to identify fonts on web pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wikiwand - Wikipedia, and beyond : AI-driven wiki aggregator created to enhance user experience on Wikipedia by streamlining knowledge consumption&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wordtune: AI Paraphrasing and Grammar Tool : Unlock your potential with Wordtune&amp;rsquo;s free AI writer – paraphrase, rewrite, translate, fix grammar, and more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You.com : Search, chat, and create with AI : Experience the future of search with generative AI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YouTube Summary with ChatGPT &amp;amp; Claude : Summarize YouTube videos, web articles, and PDFs to save time, powered by ChatGPT, Claude, Mistral AI, and Gemini.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zotero Connector : Save references to Zotero from your web browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
